Still in this sales.salesorderheader table,
let's look at the impact on space each data
type has. Space will make database designers stop
and think through which data types should be used
given different situations. Each data type
will use a certain amount of memory to store
the data in the column. For example, integers
use four bytes of data while tinyint fields
use just one byte. Elsewhere in the course, we
will cover ranges of numbers for these values.
Money fields use eight bytes of data, while
small money fields use four bytes of data.
For text, varchar uses the number of characters
plus two bytes. Thus, a 20-character varchar field
uses 22 bytes of data. Nvarchars use double
the number of characters. In other words,
a 20-character nvarchar field uses 40 bytes of
data. Elsewhere in the course, we will cover
the difference between varchar and nvarchar.
A datetime field stores eight bytes as well.